# **Marcus Holtz**

holtzweb.com	Littleton, CO
(217) 260 - 7188	marcusaholtz@gmail.com

Technical Support Engineer experienced with Linux, DevOps, programing, & customer service interested in joining a team to help with responsibilities and make accomplishments.

### **Technical Projects**

#### Homelab

My homelab features VLAN network segregation, 6 VMs, ~100 containers, multi-tier snapshoting.

#### **Resume Info**

This resume has been created in a **dockerfile** built by a **makefile** and deployed using **Github Actions' CI/CD**. The document is published everyday, with a timestamp at the last page denoting it's publishing date.

Download this document: https://github.com/MarcusHoltz/resume-generator/

### **Skills**

### **DevOps and Infrastructure**

**Virtualization** • System virtualization platforms: Docker, libvert's QEMU/KVM, VMware's vCenter and ESXi. System templates: CentOS, Ubuntu, FreeBSD, Debian, Windows in vmdk, vdi, vhdx, qcow2, & raw filetypes.

**Disaster Recovery** • Proxmox high availability ZFS solution featuring: Incremental 15min snapshotting for all VMs & persistent data using PBS2, cv4pve and Sanoid.

**Networking •** Virtualized edge routing: Linux, pfsense, OpenVSwitch, SPAN port for IDS, VLANs, DNS, BIND, VPN Installation of virtual network infrastructure: VMware ESXi, Proxmox, Hyper-V, Xen

**Containers** • LXC, containerd, docker compose, docker networking. Distributed storage technologies: NFS, Ceph, S3 as well as dynamic resource management: Kubernetes, Docker Swarm.

**Hybrid cloud administration** • Using tools such as SSH/tunneling, SSL, UDP hole punching, VPN, and single sign-on identity management.

**Edge deployment** • SSL certificate management with reverse proxy, using Traefik's YAML config added Security Onion IDS within virtualized infrastructure with additional SPAN port to duplicate internal traffic.

**Cross-platform systems administration •** Experience architecting domains across a variety of systems: Debian, CentOS, Ubuntu, FreeBSD, Microsoft Windows.

**DevOps** • Knowledge of cloud infrastructure (AWS, Azure, GCP, Oracle) & orchestration (Chef, Puppet, Ansible, SaltStack, Terraform, Helm, OpenStack).

**Programing** • Programming language and database management skills (PHP, Javascript, Python, SQL). Shell scripting with Bash.

### **Browser Privacy**

- \* Understand what data is collected by the tools you use. 11/10/22 9/3/22
  - · Link to Slides | Link to Video

#### **Opensource Firmware on Routers**

- \* What can opensource do for home consumer routers? 4/1/23
  - · Link to Slides | Link to Markdown

# **Industry Experience**

### **Leadership Activies**

#### Software Freedom School, Littleton, CO - 2022 - Present

- Software Freedom School board member since March 2023
- Maintain open tickets for SysOps board
- Presented at monthly community meetings
- Team Member in weekly Linux study group

### IT and Web Consultation / Freelancing

#### Holtzweb, Denver, CO - 2019 - Present

- Established clients' cloud based hosting environments, virtualization, and operations infrastructure.
- Strategized SEO/SEM campaigns across web presence including blogs, email newsletters, ads & promotions resulting in a 40% increase in face to face traffic and web traffic.

## Web Development

#### Highline Ideas, 1187, Mayer Networks, Carbondale, IL - 2013 - 2017

- Created and designed custom website layout/user interfaces
- Integrated data from various back-end services and databases election data, employee database, interactive event map
- Worked directly with clients to facilitate business and marking needs
- Executed tests, analyzed data to identify trends and insights using analytics tools and 3rd party optimization tools
- Ensured all site development follows web standards and ADA compliance for accessibility.
- Executed SEO-based initiatives, including website analytics and optimization.
- Fixed broken installs, hacked sites, busted databases, and never-been-updated themes/plugins.
- Repaired, updated, and redesigned new & existing sites.
- Designed custom website layout/user interfaces and custom backends to meet project dead-line/requirements.

### **Tools**

### **Software Tools Used**

Linux, bash scripting, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, Apache, Nginx, HAProxy, Traefik, Samba, Windows Server, Active Directory, GIT, VMWare vSphere, ESXi, libvert, QEMU, KVM, Xen, Hyper-V, Nagios, Docker, Vagrant, Ansible, Jenkins, Puppet, Chef, SaltStack, Helm, Kubernetes, Terraform, AWS, GCP, Oracle Cloud, Microsoft Azure, Private Cloud Hosting, Red Hat Linux (RHEL), CentOS, Debian, Ubuntu, OpenSUSE, Android, Adobe Photoshop

# **Education and Training**

BS in Finance - 2011 Southern Illinois University

Linux Foundation Certified System Administrator (LFCS): expected July 14th

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner: expected May 15th

Last Built on: Saturday 13<sup>th</sup> May, 2023